A Guide to the E.G.D. Cohen papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA1116
Rockefeller Archive Center
E.G.D. Cohen papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
ca. 1951-2006
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
Cohen, E.D.G., Dr.
FA1116
58.95 Cubic Feet
45 record storage cartons.
Separated Materials
G. E. Uhlenbeck collection: Books (originally contained in Boxes 23-26) were relocted to the RAC Library.
Arrangement
Original order, as received.
Scope and Contents
This collection is comprised of: laboratory notebooks; lecture files and notes; correspondence; administrative records; awards; research files; workshop and conference files; and a variety of reprints, papers, and manuscripts.
- E.G.D. Cohen papers, Rockefeller University Faculty, 58.95 Cubic Feet 45 standard record storage boxes
  - Mechanics papers (Box 1)
  - Lab Notebooks (Box 2)
  - Dictation Notebooks, 1946-1952; 1960 (Box 3)
  - Lab Notebooks (Box 4)
  - Lab Notebooks, 1965-1977 (Box 5)
  - Lab Notebooks, 1963-1979 (Box 6)
  - Lab Notebooks, 1960s-2001 (Box 7)
  - Lab Notebooks (Box 8)
  - Lectures and Lecture Notes, 1969-2014 (Box 9)
  - Lectures and Lecture Notes (Box 10)
  - Lectures and Lecture Notes, 1980s-2000s (Box 11)
  - Lectures and Lecture Notes, 1980s-2000s (Box 12)
  - Lectures and Lecture Notes, 1970s-2000s (Box 13)
  - Lectures and Lecture Notes, 1980s-2000s (Box 14)
  - Lectures and Lecture Notes, 1970s-2000s (Box 15)
  - Workshop, Conference and Correspondence Files - A-B, 1990s-2010s (Box 16)
  - Workshop, Conference and Correspondence Files - B-C, 1990s-2010s (Box 17)
  - Workshop, Conference and Correspondence Files - C-E, 1990s-2010s (Box 18)
  - Workshop, Conference and Correspondence Files - E-J, 1990s-2010s (Box 19)
  - Workshop, Conference and Correspondence Files - J-M, 1990s-2010s (Box 20)
  - Workshop, Conference and Correspondence Files - M, 1990s-2010s (Box 21)
  - Workshop, Conference and Correspondence Files - N-R, 1990s-2010s (Box 22)
  - Workshop, Conference and Correspondence Files - R-S, 1990s-2010s (Box 23)
  - Workshop, Conference and Correspondence Files - T-W, 1990s-2010s (Box 24)
  - Workshop, Conference and Correspondence Files - S-Z, 1990s-2010s (Box 25)
  - RU Files, Papers, and Correspondence - A-C, 2000s-2010s (Box 25)
  - RU Files, Papers, and Correspondence - C-Z, 2000s-2010s (Box 26)
  - University of Iowa Files, 2000s-2010s (Box 26)
  - Correspondence and Papers with Giovanni Gallavotti, 1990s-2010s (Box 27)
  - Notes, Papers and Correspondence (Box 28)
  - Notes, Papers, and Correspondence (Box 29)
  - Notes, Papers, and Correspondence (Box 30)
  - Notes, Papers, and Correspondence (Box 31)
  - Reprints, 1951-1981; 100 folders (Box 32)
  - Reprints, 1982-1989; 60 folders (Box 33)
  - Reprints, 1990-1994; 28 folders (Box 34)
  - Reprints, 1995-1998; 23 folders (Box 35)
  - Reprints, 1999-2001; 24 folders (Box 36)
  - Reprints, 2002-2006; 25 folders (Box 37)
  - Reprints, 2007-2010; 17 folders (Box 38)
  - Stick-slip motion paper 2010? or 2011? #1, 1 folder (Box 39)
  - Stick-slip motion paper #2, 1 folder (Box 39)
  - Stick-slip motion #3, 1 folder (Box 39)
  - Stick-slip #4, 1 folder (Box 39)
  - Not Published, 1 folder (Box 39)
  - Current Fluctuation...(Not Published) (2003) Rondoni, Gamba, Cohen, 1 folder (Box 39)
  - "Nonlinearity" Journal Article W. Rondoni- Not Submitted, 1 folder (Box 39)
  - Tahesue (Bernie), 1 folder (Box 39)
  - Temperature Echos, 1 folder (Box 39)
  - Comment on "Experimental Demonstration..." Varzon & Cohen, 2002; 1 folder (Box 39)
  - Hugo, 1 folder (Box 39)
  - Never Published, Dynamical Superstatisties Baule-Cohen, 2009; 1 folder (Box 39)
  - Never Published, Greens Functions & Hydrodynamics... Van Con + Cohen, 1 folder (Box 39)
  - Never Published, Fluctuations Theorems in nonequilibrium Statistic Mechanics: L. Rondoni et al, 1 folder (Box 39)
  - Never Publsiehd, Manog, Hugo, Egdc I Standard Text + Related Basic Material, 1 folder (Box 39)
  - Never Published, [Untitled], 1 folder (Box 39)
  - Mentoring Plan, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - 98 NSF - Wojtkowski NSF 2003, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - NSF 2005-6-7, 2005-2007; 1 folder (Box 40)
  - NSF - 2007 Grant, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - NSF 2005-7 Grant Proposal and New Data, 2005-2007; 1 folder (Box 40)
  - NSF 2009 - Final, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - Earle Lomon Marta Correspondence, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - Guidelines, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - NSF 2009 No-Cost Ext. Earle Lomon Surveys Contains Last Version of 2009 proposal, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - NSF 2010 Correspondence, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - 3/25/08 NSF - Proposal and Notification and No-Cost - proposal Data; Annual Report '07-'08, 2007-2008; 1 folder (Box 40)
  - Interessante Pre-2009 NSF Proposal - Ideiin, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - Hugo Ad NSF - proposal 2009, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - Renewal - Science, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - 2/27/09 NUGGET - NSF '09, 2009; 1 folder (Box 40)
  - Letters Bassem 2001, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - DOE Budget, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - DOE 2001, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - DOE Secty, Ken, Michael, John, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - DOE 2002, 2 folders (Box 40)
  - DOE 2004, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - DOE - Manzezall - Cohen 2006, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - DOE, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - DOE Project Period 2005-2008, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - DOE 2005-2006 Report, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - DOE Project 2002-2006, 1 folder (Box 40)
  - Verhulst, Ferdinand, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Verkerk, Peter, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Vos, Willem, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Hijmans, Herman (Cousin), 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Hijmans, Tom, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Hijams, Peter, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Hilgevooro, Jan, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Gerard 't Hooft, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - der Hollander, Frank, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Zabusky, Norman, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Troubetzkoy, Serge, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Ref. 178 (1992), 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Bogolubov & Kinetic Theory: The Bogolubov Equations, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Lectures on Non-Equilibrium Stat. Mech. + Kinetic Theory, 1987; 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Russian Version of Physics Today Paper, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Rutgers Paper 05-09-09, 2009; 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Ref. 207 # (1996), 1 folder (Box 41)
  - [Onsager-Machlup theory for nonequilibrium steady states and fluctuations theorems], 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Paper I Ness, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Paper II, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Paper III, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Survey Paper Ness Work with T. Taniguchi, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Mathem. Papers + Popov. Survey, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - OM - Quantum Mech., 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Paper IV, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Calculations and Checks, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Archives, 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Vervolgings Slachtoffers, 1 folder (Box 42)
  - Social Security, 1 folder (Box 42)
  - 240 Sutton Terrace, 1 folder (Box 42)
  - Sutton Terrace, 1 folder (Box 42)
  - Old Chase Retirement IRA's, 1 folder (Box 42)
  - A. Capitol, 1 folder (Box 42)
  - B. Select Client IRA Statements 2005&2006, 1 folder (Box 42)
  - Your TIAA-CREF Annuity Benefits Payments Statements, 1993-1999; 1 folder (Box 42)
  - Visa info bills: 212-809-4952, 1 folder (Box 42)
  - {untitled], 1 folder (Box 42)
  - Bob Francis, 1 folder (Box 42)
  - [Working Wealth], 1 folder (Box 42)
  - TIAA-CREF - 2008 - Outreach, 1 folder (Box 42)
  - Levine Tax Material for 2007 and 2006, 1 folder (Box 42)
  - [Sutton Terrace], 1 folder (Box 42)
  - Doreen, 1 folder (Box 42)
  - Warranties, 1 folder (Box 42)
  - SSB DRA, 2004-2008; 1 folder (Box 42)
  - 2003+2002+Dec 2001, 1 folder (Box 42)
  - 2000 & 2001, 1 folder (Box 42)
  - Vanguard, 1 folder (Box 42)
  - JW Lubbers, 1 folder (Box 43)
  - 1999-1994 Egdc 35258, 1994-1999; 1 folder (Box 43)
  - [Delta], 1 folder (Box 43)
  - Metropolitan Opera, 1 folder (Box 43)
  - Physical Therapy, 1 folder (Box 43)
  - [Untitled], 1 folder (Box 43)
  - Theaters, Concerts, Plays Tickets, 1 folder (Box 43)
  - MRI's Commissa 4/13/07 (Theresa!), 2007; 1 folder (Box 43)
  - Lubbers, Chr. T. Notaris, 1 folder (Box 43)
  - [Untitled], 1 folder (Box 43)
  - [SVB], 1 folder (Box 43)
  - Untitled, 1 folder (Box 43)
  - Brain Scan, 2014.045.001 (Box 43)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Records currently unavailable.
  - [Untitled], 1 folder (Box 43)
  - Mount Sinai, 1 folder (Box 43)
  - [Visiting Nurse Service of New York], 2 folders (Box 43)
  - [Untitled], 1 folder (Box 43)
  - R., 1 folder (Box 43)
  - [loose documents], 1 folder (Box 43)
  - Citizenship - Nationalization Shemer & Gensen, 1 folder (Box 43)
  - Juror Question, 1 folder (Box 43)
  - Copies of Official papers etc., 1 folder (Box 43)
  - Citizenship & Passport last corresp. end June 2004, 1 folder (Box 43)
  - Official Application & Explanatory Sheets (before Jensen & Jensen), 1 folder (Box 43)
  - Forms Citizienship Jensen & Jensen, 1 folder (Box 43)
  - Letter Jensen by Russel, 1 folder (Box 43)
  - Background Information: M.A. Cohen travel 2003-1998, 1 folder (Box 43)
  - Russell, 1 folder (Box 43)
  - Rekeningen 1999, 1 folder (Box 43)
  - [loose documents], 1 folder (Box 43)
  - 2000-1996 SSB sales at 4/11/2000 and over 2000, 1 folder (Box 44)
  - 1999-1997 EGDC + MAC 32119, 1 folder (Box 44)
  - SSB 1997, 1 folder (Box 44)
  - [Smith-Barney Shearson], 1 folder (Box 44)
  - Smith-Barney, 1 folder (Box 44)
  - Warrantees & Correspondence Sunbeam health-o-meters, 1 folder (Box 44)
  - Select Consolidation Statements & Confirmations 2005, 1 folder (Box 44)
  - Salomon Smith-Barney 2003-2004, 1 folder (Box 44)
  - 2008, 1 folder (Box 44)
  - Chase - Fraud-Abuse, 1 folder (Box 44)
  - 1990 1991-1992, 1 folder (Box 44)
  - 1993 - Oct 1994, 1 folder (Box 44)
  - 1998, 1 folder (Box 44)
  - AMRO Bank, 1 folder (Box 44)
  - [loose documents], 1 folder (Box 44)
  - Smith-Barney Bought-Sold 2008, 1 folder (Box 44)
  - D SSB Branch manager, 1 folder (Box 44)
  - Chemical Bank, 1 folder (Box 44)
  - TIAA-CRET 1999-2000, 1 folder (Box 44)
  - [Paperwork from "Diplomas Universiteit van Amsterdam en Dispuut Gezel schap Sitlium"], 1 folder (Box 44)
  - [graphs], 2 folders (Box 44)
  - Sociedad Mexicana de Fisica Oaxtepec Mor 11 Enero 14, 2014.026.002; Still Image and oversize (Box 45)
  - The Johns Hopkins Society of Scholars certificate, 2014.045.003; Oversize (Box 45)
  - Visit to USSR (+ Uzbekistan) at the invitation of Academician N.N. Bogolumbov 1976-1977, 2014.045.006; Still Image (Box SF1)
  - [Photographs], 2014.045.007; Still Image (Box SF1)
  - Lyon - Cecaun Meeting July 1996, 2014.045.004; Still Image (Box SF2)
  - [untitled portrait], 2014.045.005; Still Image (Box SF2)
  - [two portraits on board], 2014.045.008; Still Image (Box SF2)
  - Universitatis Amstelodamensis, 2014.045.009; Oversize (Roll 1)
  - [Diploma], 2014.045.010; Oversize